<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>koyu.space Blog</title><link>https://blog.koyu.space/</link><description>Recent content on koyu.space Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 10:11:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.koyu.space/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The all new koyu.space Blog</title><link>https://blog.koyu.space/2021/07/25/the-all-new-koyuspace-blog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.koyu.space/2021/07/25/the-all-new-koyuspace-blog/</guid><description>The koyu.space Blog got a fresh coat of paint and is now based on Hugo. The whole site should now load a lot faster and everything should also look nicer as well. I hope you like the changes as we do. Since this blog has been inactive a long time now it was time to redo the whole thing and see what we can do to post more stuff over here.</description></item><item><title>Moving away from Kubernetes</title><link>https://blog.koyu.space/2021/03/07/moving-away-from-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 10:11:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.koyu.space/2021/03/07/moving-away-from-kubernetes/</guid><description>This Saturday we moved away from Kubernetes and in this blog post we want to explain how and why we did it.
How we did it Of course we backed up the whole database and imported it to a new host. Since our media is stored in S3 we didn’t have to move this as well. After the database was imported to the new host I began installing koyu.space to the new host and changing the .</description></item><item><title>The thing with Trump’s Twitter account</title><link>https://blog.koyu.space/2021/01/09/the-thing-with-trumps-twitter-account/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 09:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.koyu.space/2021/01/09/the-thing-with-trumps-twitter-account/</guid><description>Trump has been banned from Twitter today, as many are celebrating this event I want to give some insights on why this happened and give some comments on this.
Terms of Service By signing up for any internet service you are agreeing to the Terms of Service of that specific platform. You can kind of think of like the house rules in a bar everyone has to follow. If the barkeeper doesn’t like you and thinks you violated their house rules they’ll kick you out.</description></item><item><title>The months on koyu.space (September &amp; October 2020)</title><link>https://blog.koyu.space/2020/11/05/the-months-on-koyu-space-september-october-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 09:56:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.koyu.space/2020/11/05/the-months-on-koyu-space-september-october-2020/</guid><description>The development work is now over for September and October 2020 and we are ready to present everything that happened around koyu.space to you. A lot of things happened and we don’t want you to miss out on all these important changes.
Fix image uploads We finally fixed broken images showing up everywhere on koyu.space and we hope you’ll like this change.
Post notifications Wanted to know when the least active person in your feed posted something after a while?</description></item><item><title>The months on koyu.space (July 2020)</title><link>https://blog.koyu.space/2020/08/04/the-months-on-koyu-space-july-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 09:45:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.koyu.space/2020/08/04/the-months-on-koyu-space-july-2020/</guid><description>The development work is now over for July 2020 and we are ready to present everything that happened around koyu.space to you. A lot of things happened and we don’t want you to miss out on all these important changes.
koyu.space on VHS koyu.space now has its own PeerTube instance. This is a core service and wouldn’t be shut down. PeerTube functions like YouTube, but decentralized (with ActivityPub and WebTorrent). The difference is that if a video on koyu.</description></item><item><title>The months on koyu.space (August 2020)</title><link>https://blog.koyu.space/2020/08/03/the-months-on-koyu-space-august-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 09:40:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.koyu.space/2020/08/03/the-months-on-koyu-space-august-2020/</guid><description>The development work is now over for August 2020 and we are ready to present everything that happened around koyu.space to you. A lot of things happened and we don’t want you to miss out on all these important changes.
Fixing repetitive downtimes The repeated downtimes of koyu.space are now resolved.
The hosting provider of the routing server had messed up something since the 11th of August.
Despite many, stressful, nights spent trying to resolve it (i.</description></item><item><title>koyu.space and what the Keybase/Zoom acquisition means</title><link>https://blog.koyu.space/2020/07/05/koyu-space-and-what-the-keybase-zoom-acquisition-means/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 09:53:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.koyu.space/2020/07/05/koyu-space-and-what-the-keybase-zoom-acquisition-means/</guid><description>Keybase has been acquired by Zoom. This is huge news for us, but it also means that a company known to create secure software is now in the hands of a company that had done years of damage to privacy and user trust. Today we are not going to support Keybase in the future and cease any integration of Keybase into koyu.space services. This also means you have to download new builds for the koyu.</description></item><item><title>The months on koyu.space (June 2020)</title><link>https://blog.koyu.space/2020/07/02/the-months-on-koyu-space-june-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 09:51:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.koyu.space/2020/07/02/the-months-on-koyu-space-june-2020/</guid><description>The development work is now over for June 2020 and we are ready to present everything that happened around koyu.space to you. A lot of things happened and we don’t want you to miss out on all these important changes.
koyu.space Discuss We opened up our first discussion forum for koyu.space. Having a forum has a few more advantages over a traditional social network. Posts can be indefinitely long and have even richer formatting options than we already have on our Mastodon instance.</description></item><item><title>The months on koyu.space (May 2020)</title><link>https://blog.koyu.space/2020/06/03/the-months-on-koyu-space-may-2020/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 09:55:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.koyu.space/2020/06/03/the-months-on-koyu-space-may-2020/</guid><description>The development work is now over for May 2020 and we are ready to present everything that happened around koyu.space to you. A lot of things happened and we don’t want you to miss out on all these important changes.
The big migration We migrated from masto.host to our own infrastructure and it was a huge success. This gives is a lot more flexibility over what software can run on the server and a lot more scalability.</description></item><item><title>The months on koyu.space (March-April 2020)</title><link>https://blog.koyu.space/2020/04/14/the-months-on-koyu-space-march-april-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 09:35:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.koyu.space/2020/04/14/the-months-on-koyu-space-march-april-2020/</guid><description>The development work is now over for April 2020 and we are ready to present everything that happened around koyu.space to you. A lot of things happened and we don’t want you to miss out on all these important changes.
The big summer migration You might have heard that we are going to migrate to a new host on June 26 2020 (note that down in your calendar). This means we would then have a lot more flexibility than we already have which also means that it will allow us to introduce new features.</description></item></channel></rss>